What we're going to talk about today, is goals.
今天我们要讲的，是目标。
So just by way of a little warm up exercise, I'd like you to look at that integration problem
因此，通过一些热身练习，我希望你看看
over there. The one that's disappeared.
那边的集成问题。 消失的那个。
So the question is, can you do it in your head? Probably not. The question is, if a
所以问题是，你能在你的头脑中做到这一点吗？ 可能不是。 问题是，如果一个
program can do that, is a program, in any sense of the word, intelligent? That's a background
程序可以做到这一点，那么程序，在任何意义上，是智能的吗？ 这
task I'd like you to work on as I talk today.
是我今天讲话时希望你完成的一项背景任务。
So today we're going to be modeling a little bit of human
所以今天我们将模拟一些人类
problem solving, the kind that
问题的解决方法，
is required when you do symbolic integration. Now, you all learned how to do that. You may
当你进行符号集成时需要这种方法。现在，你们都学会了如何做到这一点。 你
not be able to do that particular problem anymore, but you all learned how to integrate
可能无法再做那个特定的问题，但你们都学会了如何
in high school 1801, or something like that. The question is, how did you do it, and is
融入高中 1801 或类似的东西。问题是，你是怎么做到的，以及
the problem solving technique that we are trying to model by building a program that
我们试图通过构建一个进行符号集成的程序来建模的问题解决技术
does symbolic integration, is that a common kind of description of what people do when
，是人们在解决问题时所做的一种常见描述
they solve problems.
。
So the answer to the question is, yes. The kind of problem solving you'll see
所以这个问题的答案是，是的。 您今天将看到的解决问题的
today is like generating tests, which you saw last time. It's a very common kind of
方法就像您上次看到的生成测试一样。 这是一种非常常见的
problem solving that we all engage in, that we all engage in without thinking about it,
解决问题的方法，我们都在参与，我们都在不考虑它的情况下参与，
and without having a name for it.
也没有为它命名。
But once we get a name for it, we'll get power over it. And then we'll be able to deploy
但是一旦我们得到它的名字，我们就会得到控制它的权力。 然后我们将能够部署
it, and it will become a skill. We'll not just witness it, we'll not just understand
它，它将成为一项技能。 我们不会只是目睹它，我们不会只是理解
it, we'll use it instinctively, as a skill.
它，我们会本能地使用它，作为一种技能。
So there you are, you've got that problem, there's your problem, and what do you do to
所以你来了，你有那个问题，你的问题，你怎么
solve it? I don't know, look it up in a table? You'll never find it in a table because of
解决它？ 不知道，在表格里查一下？因为那个减号和那个 5，你永远不会在表格中找到它
that minus sign and that 5. So you're going to have to do something better than that.
。所以你将不得不做一些比这更好的事情。
So what you're going to do, is what you always do when you see a problem like that. You try
所以你要做的就是当你看到这样的问题时你总是做的。 您
to apply a transform, and make it into a different problem that's easier to solve. And eventually,
尝试应用转换，并将其变成更容易解决的不同问题。 最终，
what you hope is that you'll simplify it sufficiently, that the pieces that you've simplified to
你希望你能充分简化它，你已经简化的部分
will be found in some small table of integrals. So how long is this table? It's not the case
将在一些小的积分表中找到。那么这张桌子有多长呢？
that we're going to look at a table with 388 elements, because this is not a big table
我们不是要查看一个包含 388 个元素的表，因为这不是一个大
of integrals. This is what a freshman might have in a freshman's head, after taking a
的积分表。 这是一个新生在
course in integral calculus.
学习了积分微积分课程后可能会想到的。
One of the interesting questions is, how many elements have to be in that table to get an
一个有趣的问题是，该表中必须有多少元素才能
A in the course? We're interested in how much knowledge is involved, that's one of the elements
在课程中获得 A？ 我们感兴趣的是涉及到多少知识，这
of catechism that I've listed over there, that will be part of the gold star ideas suite
是我在那里列出的要理问答的要素之一，这将成为当天的金星创意套件
of the day.
的一部分。
So we'd like to take that problem, and find a way to make it into another problem that's
所以我们想解决这个问题，并找到一种方法将其变成另一个
more likely, or closer to being found in the table. So what we're going to do is very simple,
更有可能或更接近于在表格中找到的问题。 所以我们要做的非常简单，
graphically. We're going to take the problem we're given, and convert it into another problem
图形化。 我们将处理我们给出的问题，并将其转换为另一个
that's simpler. And we're going to give that process and name, and we're going to call
更简单的问题。 我们将给出该过程和名称，我们将
it problem reduction.
称之为问题减少。
And so, in the world of integral calculus, there are all sorts of simple methods, simple
所以，在积分学的世界里，有各种简单的方法，简单的
transformations, we can try that will take a hard problem and make it into an easier
变换，我们可以尝试把难的问题变成更容易的
problem. And some of these transformations are extremely simple and always safe. Some
问题。 其中一些转换非常简单且始终安全。
of them are just, well let's try it and see what happens. But some of them are safe, and
其中一些只是，让我们尝试一下，看看会发生什么。 但是其中一些是安全的，
I'd like to make a short list of safe transformations right now.
我现在想列出一个安全转换的简短列表。
Now I'm going to be going into some detail. And that detail will be grungy. And the question
现在我将详细介绍。而且那个细节会很蹩脚。 问题
is, why do I do it? And it's educational philosophy, is why I do it. So here's the educational
是，我为什么要这样做？ 这是教育理念，是我这样做的原因。 这就是教育
philosophy. At one level, you want to have a skill. But if you're going to have a skill,
理念。 在一个层面上，你想拥有一项技能。 但是，如果您要掌握一项技能，
you have to understand it. So if you're going to have a skill you have to understand it
则必须了解它。 因此，如果您要掌握一项技能，则必须将其理解低
one level down. If you're going to understand it, you have to have witnessed it on a level
一级。 如果你要理解它，你必须在比这更低的层次上见证它
lower than that.
。
So I'm not just going to talk about the idea of problem reduction, because if I were just
所以我不只是谈论减少问题的想法，因为如果我
going to do that, then we could all go home now. So I'm going to show you a particular
只是这样做，那么我们现在都可以回家了。 因此，我将向您展示它的一个特定
example of it, so you understand it better, and I'm going to show you the detail at an
示例，以便您更好地理解它，并且我将向您展示
even lower level than that. So you will witness the stuff that makes it possible, to understand
比这更低级别的细节。 因此，您将见证使之成为可能的东西，了解
the stuff that makes it possible, to build a skill. So that's why I'm going through the
使之成为可能的东西，并建立技能。 所以这就是为什么我要通过
grungy detail.
蹩脚的细节。
So I don't know, let's see. Maybe we can get some hints from that example, but I wonder
所以我不知道，让我们看看。 也许我们可以从那个例子中得到一些提示，但我想知道
if somebody could volunteer a simple transformation that always is a good thing to do. Yes, Sebastian.
是否有人可以自愿进行一个简单的转换，这总是一件好事。 是的，塞巴斯蒂安。
AUDIENCE: Take the constants out.
听众：去掉常数。
SPEAKER 1: Take the constants out. So we'll make that number two. And we'll say that the
SPEAKER 1：取出常数。 所以我们将把它排在第二位。 我们会说
integral c f of x dx is equal to c times the integral f of x dx. Other suggestions? Yes.
x dx 的积分 c f 等于 c 乘以 x dx 的积分 f。 其他建议？ 是的。
AUDIENCE: Trig substitution.
听众：三角替换。
SPEAKER 1: Trig substitution. Now this is-- no, that's for day two. We don't do trig substitution
扬声器 1：三角替换。 现在这是 -不，这是第二天的。 我们不会
here under stuff that's safe, always works, never any doubt, there are simpler things.
在安全、始终有效、毫无疑问的东西下进行三角替换，还有更简单的东西。
These are the safe transformations. What you're giving me is a heuristic transformation. Often
这些是安全的转换。 你给我的是启发式转换。 通常
is helpful, doesn't necessarily always work. We're going to divide our transformations
是有帮助的，不一定总是有效的。我们将把我们的转换
into those two categories. So I need another safe one.
分为这两类。 所以我需要另一个安全的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
SPEAKER 1: The architects are sitting over there. Divided not only by nationality, but
发言者 1：建筑师们坐在那边。 不仅按国籍划分，而且
by course. What?
按课程划分。 什么？
AUDIENCE: The sum of integrals is the integral of the sum.
听众：积分的总和是总和的积分。
SPEAKER 1: The sum of integrals is the integral of the sum. Now what's missing? What's number
SPEAKER 1：积分之和是总和的积分。 现在缺少什么？ 什么是
one? You're probably thinking it's already there, because you've given me the transformation
第一？ 你可能认为它已经存在，因为你给了我
that involves a constant. And you can think of minus 1 as a constant.
一个涉及常数的转换。 您可以将负 1 视为一个常数。
But whether you use a separate transformation or not, of course depends on how you represent
但是，是否使用单独的转换当然取决于您如何
the knowledge. And all of this knowledge, all of this whole thing, was written in an
表示知识。 所有这些知识，所有这一切，都是用
early form of Lisp. As a consequence, the way in which minus was represented is different
Lisp 的早期形式编写的。 因此，表示负的方式与
from the way minus 1 is represented. So we need one more transformation. Or rather, Jim
表示负 1 的方式不同。 所以我们需要再一次转变。 或者更确切地说，Jim
Slagle needed one more transformation, when he wrote his famous transformation program.
Slagle 在编写他著名的转换程序时需要再进行一次转换。
And that was that if you have the integral of minus f of x, that's equal to, minus the
那就是如果你有x 的负 f 的积分，那就等于，减去
integral of f of x.
x 的 f 的积分。
So that almost completes our safe transformation set. There's one more that I'm going to supply
这样就几乎完成了我们的安全转换集。 我还要给
you, because I don't think you'd guess it. Why should you? It's number four. There are
你一个，因为我想你不会猜到的。你为什么要？ 是第四个。 还有
more than this, this is a sample. And these are the ones we're going to need in order
更多，这是一个样本。 这些是我们为了解决这个问题而需要的
to solve that problem, by way of illustration.
，通过说明。
So the fourth one is that, if you have the integral of p of x, over q of x, then you
所以第四个是，如果你有x 的 p 在 x 的 q 上的积分，那么你
divide. If you can reach way back into high school and figure out how to divide polynomials.
除法。 如果您可以回到高中并弄清楚如何划分多项式。
But if the degree of the numerator is greater than the degree of the denominator, then it's
但是如果分子的次数大于分母的次数，那
a knee-jerk always win, you must do it, divide it out.
就是下意识的总是赢，你必须这样做，把它分开。
So this, then, forms the core of an integration program, that will integrate almost nothing.
因此，这构成了集成程序的核心，它几乎不会集成任何内容。
But actually, almost nothing is integrable anyway, so it's a good head start. So let's
但实际上，几乎没有什么是可积的，所以这是一个很好的开始。 因此，让
see how we would put this into some kind of procedure. Some kind of framework for deploying
我们看看如何将其放入某种程序中。 某种用于部署
the knowledge that we're beginning to develop.
我们开始开发的知识的框架。
What we're going to do is, apply all safe transforms. That's our first step. Then we're
我们要做的是，应用所有安全转换。 这是我们的第一步。 然后我们
going to look in the table, and then we're going to do a test to see if we're done. And
将查看表格，然后我们将进行测试，看看我们是否完成了。
if we are, we report success. But, we're not likely to get done with just that stuff.
如果我们是，我们报告成功。 但是，我们不可能只完成这些东西。
But you know what, there was one transformation up here, which breaks my little diagram. Which
但是你知道吗，这里有一个转变，打破了我的小图表。 哪
one is it? It's the third one, right? Because this picture does not reflect what happens
一个？ 是第三个吧？ 因为这张图片没有反映
when you apply number three. Because it breaks the problem up, not into just one problem,
当你应用第三个时会发生什么。 因为它把问题分解，不仅仅是一个问题，
but into a whole bunch. So we have to extend our graphical device for talking about this
而是一大堆问题。 所以我们必须扩展我们的图形设备来讨论
by a little bit, and show what is called an "and node".
这个问题，并显示所谓的“和节点”。
So we've got a program core, we've got a table of integrals, we've got a few transformations,
所以我们有一个程序核心，我们有一个积分表，我们有一些转换，
we've got an architecture, a way of putting that stuff together. And now we can try it
我们有一个架构，一种将这些东西放在一起的方法。 现在我们可以
out on our sample problem. So let's have a go at that.
在我们的示例问题上进行尝试。 因此，让我们尝试一下。
Let's see, this one immediately transforms into 5x to the fourth over 1 minus x squared
让我们看看，这个立即转换为 5x 到 1 减去 x 平方
to the 5/2 dx. And that in turn, immediately transforms into the integral of x to the fourth
到 5/2 dx 的四分之一。 反过来，它立即转换为 x 对 4 的积分，
over 1 minus x squared to the 5/2, dx.
超过 1 减去 x 的 5/2 平方，dx。
This program, by the way, is a dawn-age program. This was written by a nearly blind, and subsequently
顺便说一句，这个程序是一个黎明时代的程序。这是很久以前的 1960 年，一位几乎失明，后来
completely blind, graduate student by the name of James Slagle in 1960, a long time
完全失明的研究生 James Slagle 写的
ago. The reason I gave it to you today is because, that by describing it, I am giving
。 我今天给你的原因是，通过描述它，我给
you a one-lecture course in artificial intelligence. He anticipated so much of the subsequent 20
你上了一门人工智能课程。在接下来的 20 年里，他对未来的 20
years, that talking about his program, which is possible in one day, is a miniature introduction
年充满了期待，以至于谈论他的计划，这可能在一天之内成为可能，是
to the whole field.
对整个领域的一个缩影。
So Slagle, as he was doing this on an antique computer, almost no memory, almost no speed,
所以Slagle，当他在一台古董电脑上做这件事时，几乎没有记忆，几乎没有速度，
only slightly faster than mice running around on a treadmill. He was able to write a program
只比在跑步机上跑来跑去的老鼠快一点。 他能够编写一个
that did extremely well when benchmarked against freshmen. And the way you benchmark against
在与新生进行基准测试时表现非常出色的程序。 当然，你对大一学生进行基准测试的方式
freshman, of course, is you give it an examination, drawn from the previous MIT finals for four
是你给它一个考试，从之前四五年的麻省理工总决赛中抽取
or five years, the hardest problems. And this was the hardest problem that it solved.
，最难的问题。 这是它解决的最困难的问题。
So at this point, with what we've got so far, we would be stuck. We have no transformation
所以在这一点上，就我们目前所拥有的而言，我们会被卡住。 我们没有
that can take us further, so we need something else. And what we need by way of something
可以带我们走得更远的转变，所以我们需要别的东西。 通过其他方式，我们需要的
else, is some transformations that we will describe as-- perhaps we'll call them, heuristic
是一些我们将描述为的转换——也许我们会称它们为启发式
transformations. A funny word, meaning a method that often works isn't guaranteed to work.
转换。 一个有趣的词，意思是经常有效的方法并不能保证有效。
It's not an algorithm in the usual sense that we talk about algorithms. But rather, it's
我们所说的算法不是通常意义上的算法。 但更确切地说，这是
an attempt.
一种尝试。
So these things I'm going to talk about now, are sometimes useful, not always useful. Sometimes
所以我现在要谈的这些东西，有时有用，但并不总是有用。 有时
take you into a blind alley, don' always work. But you can't get an A in calculus without
会把你带入死胡同，不要总是工作。但是你不能在不
knowing some of them. So you said, some kind of trig substitution. So here is some kind
知道其中一些的情况下在微积分中获得 A。 所以你说，某种三角替换。 所以这是
of trig substitution. We'll call this heuristic transformation A.
某种三角替换。 我们将这种启发式变换称为 A。
You have a function sine x, cosine x, tangent of x, cotangent of x, secant of x, and cosecant
您有一个函数正弦 x、余弦 x、x 的正切、x 的余切、x 的割线和 x 的余割线
of x. And we all know from high school trigonometry, that we can rewrite that as a function of
。 我们都从高中三角学中知道，我们可以将其重写为
sine x, and cosine x. Or we can rewrite that as a function of tangent of x, and cosecant
正弦 x 和余弦 x 的函数。 或者我们可以将其重写为 x 的正切和 x 的余割
of x. Or we can rewrite that as function of cotangent of x, and the secant of x. So that's
的函数。 或者我们可以将其重写为 x 的余切和 x 的割线的函数。 所以这是
a transmission from trigonometric form, into another trigonometric form. It's not always
从三角函数形式到另一种三角函数形式的转换。 这并不总是
a good idea, sometimes it helps.
一个好主意，有时它会有所帮助。
Well that's just part one of our suite of heuristic transformations. Stop. There are
这只是我们启发式转换套件的一部分。 停止。 为了解决问题
others that we need to have in our repertoire, in order to solve the problem. One of them
，我们需要在我们的曲目中拥有其他内容。 其中一个
is a family of transformations, which I'll show you only one. It goes like this, if you
是一系列转换，我将只向您展示一个。 它是这样的，如果你
have the integral of a function, of the tangent of x, then you can rewrite that as the integral
有一个函数的积分，x 的正切，那么你可以将它重写为
of a function of y over 1 plus y squared dy. So that's a transformation from a trigonometric
y 在 1 加上 y 平方 dy 上的函数的积分。所以这是从三角函数
form into a polynomial form. So it gets rid of all that trigonometric garbage we don't
形式到多项式形式的转换。 所以它摆脱了所有我们不想处理的三角函数垃圾
want to deal with. And there's a whole family of things like that, just as there's a family
。 有一整套这样的东西，就像有一整套
of transformations like so, but this is enough to give you flavor.
这样的转变，但这足以给你带来味道。
Now there's a C that we need as well. And that's going to be your proper knee-jerk reaction
现在我们也需要一个 C。 当您看到 1 减去 x 平方的形式时，这将是您正确的下意识反应
when you see something of the form 1 minus x squared. What do you do when you see that?
。 当你看到它时你会怎么做？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]那
What's that Rhana?
是什么Rhana？
Rhana: 1 + 6  * 1 - 6
Rhana：1 + 6 * 1 - 6
Well wait a second. We could do that. But there's another thing we can do.
等一下。 我们可以这样做。但我们还可以做另一件事。
Christian, have you got something you can suggest? Where's our Hungarian? Our Turk,
克里斯蒂安，你有什么可以建议的吗？ 我们的匈牙利人在哪里？ 我们的土耳其人，
our young Turk. Yeah, what do you think?
我们年轻的土耳其人。 是啊，你怎么看？
AUDIENCE: I actually don't remember. I mean, I think it might have been 10.
听众：我其实不记得了。 我的意思是，我想可能是 10。
SPEAKER 1: Well, let's see. Cosine squared plus sine squared equals 1. So, what's that
发言者 1：好吧，让我们看看。 余弦平方加上正弦平方等于 1。那么，这
suggest to you? So it suggests that we make a transformation that involves x equals sine
对您有什么建议？ 所以它建议我们进行一个涉及 x 等于 sine y 的变换
y. So [? Silla ?] doesn't actually have to remember that anymore because going forward,
。 所以 [？  Silla ?] 实际上不必再记住这一点，因为今后
she will never have to integrate anything personally in her life, she can just simulate
她将永远不必亲自将任何东西融入她的生活中，她只需
the program.
模拟程序即可。
So these go from polynomial form, back into trigonometric form. So you have three of these
所以这些从多项式形式回到三角函数形式。 所以你有这些
heuristic transformations. We've got four safe transformations. Let's see if we can
启发式转换中的三个。 我们有四个安全的转换。 让我们看看我们是否可以
make any progress on our integration problem.
在集成问题上取得任何进展。
OK so keeping track of what we've been using, this is safe transformation number one, this
好的，所以跟踪我们一直在使用的东西，这是第一安全转换，这
is safe transformation number two. What do we do next? We decided there were no more
是第二安全转换。我们接下来要做什么？ 我们决定不再
safe transformations that apply. But now we can look at our heuristic transformations
有适用的安全转换。 但是现在我们可以看看我们的启发式转换
and behold, we see what?
，瞧，我们看到了什么？
AUDIENCE: C
听众：C
SPEAKER 1: What?
发言者 1：什么？
AUDIENCE: Applying transformation C.
听众：应用变换 C。
SPEAKER 1: Transformation C suggests that we do x equals the sine y.
演讲者 1：变换 C 表明我们做 x 等于 sine y。
And now we get the integral of sine to the
现在我们得到正弦对
fourth y over cosine to the fourth y dy, right. All good, I see some confused, worried, concerned
第四个 y 的积分，余弦对第四个 y dy 的积分，对。一切都好，我看到一些困惑、担心、担心的
looks. Maybe I've made a mistake, perhaps I should use notes. Well no, wait a minute.
表情。 也许我犯了一个错误，也许我应该使用笔记。 不，等一下。
For those of you who have a concerned look, remember that if x equals a sine y, then dx
对于那些关心的人，请记住，如果 x 等于 sine y，则 dx
is equal to cosine y dy. That's why it's cosine to the fourth not cosine to the fifth, as
等于 cosine y dy。 这就是为什么它是第四次的余弦而不是第五次的余弦，正如
you were perhaps thinking it might be.
您可能认为的那样。
So now we've made some progress. We look at this, we say, are there any safe transformations
所以现在我们已经取得了一些进展。 我们看看这个，我们说，是否有
that apply? And the answer is, no. Now we look for a heuristic transformation that might
任何适用的安全转换？ 答案是，不。 现在我们寻找一个可能适用的启发式变换
apply, and I say, what do you see? Which one? What's that?
，我说，你看到了什么？ 哪一个？那是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
SPEAKER 1: She said something unintelligible, but what she probably said is, that this looks
演讲者 1：她说了一些难以理解的话，但她可能说的是，这看起来
like a pattern that might match with the heuristic transformation A, right? Because we have a
像是一个可能与启发式变换 A 匹配的模式，对吧？ 因为我们有一个
function in which the variable is buried, universally in sines, or cosines, or tangents,
函数，其中变量被掩埋，普遍存在于正弦、或余弦、或正切、
or cotangents, or secants, or cosecants. And we know we can rewrite that in one of three
或余切、或正割或余割中。我们知道我们可以用三种方式之一重写它
ways. It's already written as a function of sine and cosine. But we can also rewrite that
。 它已经写成正弦和余弦的函数。 但是我们也可以
in terms of tangent and cosecant. Or cotangent and secant.
用正切和余割来重写它。 或余切和割线。
So when we do that, we can go this way, and we can get the integral of 1 over the cotangent
所以当我们这样做时，我们可以这样走，我们可以得到 1 在
of x dx. That's g3 up there. Or we can do it down this path, and get the integral of
x dx 的余切上的积分。 上面是g3。 或者我们可以沿着这条路做，得到
tangent of x dx. And of course, those are both to the fourth.
x dx 的正切积分。 当然，这些都是第四个。
But know what, I've broken my little graphical diagram again. Where did it go, it's disappeared.
但是知道吗，我又把我的小图形图弄坏了。 去了哪里，消失了。
There it is. How have I broken it? Because with transformation A, I've introduced a possibility
它在那里。 我怎么破了？ 因为通过转换 A，我引入了一种可能性
that a particular problem can be transformed into more than one kind of problem, any of
，即一个特定的问题可以转换为不止一种问题，其中任何
which will be the solution to my problem.
一种都可以解决我的问题。
So far I've got an and node, but now I've got to introduce an or node. Because now we
到目前为止，我已经有了一个 and 节点，但现在我必须介绍一个 or 节点。 因为现在我们
have an example of something that can be solved one of two different ways, and we don't care
有一个可以用两种不同方法之一解决的例子，我们不在乎
which one it is. Now you'll notice that there's already some confusion here, because how can
它是哪一种。 现在您会注意到这里已经有些混乱了，因为
you tell the difference between an and node and an or node. So the universal convention
您如何区分 an and 节点和 an or 节点之间的区别。 所以通用约定
is, you draw an arc over the and nodes. And that makes it look like an A, so it's easy
是，在 和 节点上画一条弧线。这使它看起来像一个A，所以很
to remember. So those are and nodes.
容易记住。 所以那些是和节点。
And now, we have the method of problem reduction, and this is sometimes called a problem reduction
现在，我们有了问题缩减的方法，这有时被称为问题缩减
tree. Sometimes it's called an and/or tree, and sometimes it's called a goal tree, because
树。 有时它被称为和/或树，有时它被称为目标树，因为
this tree of problems is a tree that shows how our goals are related to one another.
这棵问题树是一棵树，它显示了我们的目标如何相互关联。
So these are items for your vocabulary that are all synonymous. Problem reduction tree,
所以这些都是你的词汇表的同义词。 问题减少树，
and/or tree, goal tree, all the same thing. Now you have a name for it, you've got some
和/或树，目标树，都是一样的。现在你有了它的名字，你对它有一些
power over it. So when we get a situation like this, unlike the previous situation,
权力。 所以当我们遇到这样的情况时，与之前的情况不同
which we suggested might come up in transformation A. Let's see, we've got one, two, C, and this
，我们建议在转换 A 中可能会出现这种情况。让我们看看，我们有一个，两个，C，这个
one is A, it's an or node. Which one of these problems do we work on?
是 A，它是一个或节点。我们要解决这些问题中的哪一个？
Well Slegle, who considered himself to be modeling a freshman, modeling the intelligence
好吧，Slegle，他认为自己是在为新生做模特，
of a freshman, modeling something that, after all, you have to be pretty smart to do, right.
在为新生的智力建模，在做一些你必须非常聪明才能做的事情，对吧。
Most people don't know how to do integration. Everybody at MIT knows how to do integration.
大多数人不知道如何进行集成。麻省理工学院的每个人都知道如何进行集成。
You would think that somebody, therefore, that knows how to do integration is pretty
因此，您会认为知道如何进行集成的人非常
smart. What would a smart person do, when faced with this choice?
聪明。 一个聪明的人在面对这个选择时会怎么做？
Well, a smart person would say, which of these two problems is easier? So how do you think
好吧，聪明的人会说，这两个问题哪个更容易？ 那么，您认为
you might determine which of two, or many algebraic expressions is the easiest to integrate?
如何确定两个或多个代数表达式中的哪一个最容易集成？
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
AUDIENCE: Andrew Carrol.
听众：安德鲁·卡罗尔。
SPEAKER 1: Andrew, what do you think?
发言者 1：安德鲁，你怎么看？
AUDIENCE: Based on whichever one feels more familiar.
听众：基于感觉更熟悉的那个。
SPEAKER 1: Feels.
发言者 1：感觉。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
SPEAKER 1: Feels.
发言者 1：感觉。
AUDIENCE: You asked, how would I decide.
听众：你问，我将如何决定。
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, how would you decide? How would you feel it?
发言者 1：是的，你会如何决定？你会怎么想？
AUDIENCE: I would feel that the tangent is more familiar.
听众：我觉得切线比较熟悉。
SPEAKER 1: Which one?
演讲者 1：哪一个？
AUDIENCE: I feel that the tangent [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我觉得切线[听不清]。
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, but I wonder how we could make it a little bit more precise, this idea
演讲者 1：是的，但我想知道我们如何才能使它更精确一点，这种
of simplicity. The young Turk has a suggestion. What?
简单的想法。 年轻的土耳其人有一个建议。什么？
AUDIENCE: I had a suggestion until you said this idea of simplicity. So then I realized
听众：我有一个建议，直到你说这个简单的想法。 所以后来我
that what I was about to suggest wasn't going to clarify simplicity, but I was going to
意识到我要建议的并不是要澄清简单性，而是我
say, whichever one we've had more encounters with, or more experience with.
要说的是，无论我们遇到过更多的人，还是有更多的经验。
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, if there was something here with a hyperbolic tangent, you might say,
演讲者 1：是的，如果这里有什么东西是双曲正切，你可能会说，
well, stay away from that. [? Yinid ?]?
好吧，远离那个。  [？ 伊尼德？]？
AUDIENCE: To which one of those the easier transformation is applied on the next step.
听众：下一步将应用更容易的转换。
SPEAKER 1: Like, somebody do a little look ahead, and see which kind of thing would be
演讲者 1：比如，有人向前看，看看你旁边会出现哪种东西
next to you? I don't know, maybe. Oh, we've got lots of people, all at the same time.
？ 我不知道，也许吧。 哦，我们有很多人，都在同一时间。
I don't know all your names yet. Shoot. Erica, I know you.
我还不知道你所有的名字。 射击。 艾丽卡，我认识你。
AUDIENCE: What's look it up in the table and see [INAUDIBLE].
听众：在表格中查找什么，看看[听不清]。
SPEAKER 1: Oh, you could look it up in the table and see if something is in it, you could
发言者 1：哦，你可以在表里查一下，看看里面有没有东西，你可以
do that. But this is tangent to the fourth, so that's not in the table. Ariel?
这样做。 但这与第四个相切，所以不在表格中。 爱丽儿？
AUDIENCE: I choose the one without the reciprocal.
听众：我选择没有倒数的那个。
SPEAKER 1: Why?
演讲者 1：为什么？
AUDIENCE: It is because when people see one it's like, oh man, it jut not going to work.
听众：这是因为当人们看到一个时，就像，哦，伙计，它根本不起作用。
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, we're on the right track. Claire?
发言者 1：是的，我们走在正确的轨道上。克莱尔？
AUDIENCE: On an extremely simple level, I choose whichever one has the least symbols
听众：在一个非常简单的层面上，我选择其中符号最少的一个
in it.
。
SPEAKER 1: The fewest symbols in it. Now we're really getting somewhere, because you can
SPEAKER 1：其中最少的符号。 现在我们真的到了某个地方，因为你可以
measure that, right, there's a little program Why Brett, there you are.
测量它，对，有一个小程序为什么 Brett，你在那儿。
AUDIENCE: I would say, every [INAUDIBLE] expression can be written as, having a number of functions,
听众：我想说，每个 [听不清] 表达式都可以写成，有许多函数，
we could say all these functions, multiplied together, divided, and you can just choose
我们可以说所有这些函数，相乘，相除，你可以
with the least amount of [? iterations ?].
用最少的 [? 迭代？]。
SPEAKER 1: Well I heard it, perhaps others didn't but what Brett said, is he suggested
演讲者 1：嗯，我听说了，也许其他人没有，但 Brett 说的是，他
that we should measure depth of functional composition. So the number of symbols may
建议我们应该测量功能组合的深度。 所以符号的数量可能
not matter, because if you have x plus x plus x plus x, out to a hundred, that would not
无关紧要，因为如果你有 x 加 x 加x 加 x，到一百个，那
be hard to integrate. But if you've got something that is really deeply nested under a lot of
将不难整合。 但是，如果你有一些真正深深嵌套在许多功能组合下的东西
functional compositions, that could be a problem. And that's in fact, what Slegle decided to
，那可能是个问题。事实上，这正是 Slegle
use, after trying several alternatives.
在尝试了几种替代方案后决定使用的。
So if we measure the depth of the functional composition, this is the winner, and we put
因此，如果我们衡量功能组合的深度，这是赢家，我们
the other one on the shelf, at least for the moment. And now we have tangent to the fourth
将另一个放在架子上，至少目前是这样。 现在我们与第四个
x dx. Do I need the safe transformation supply? No. Which of the-- you know something has
x dx 相切。 我需要安全的转换供应吗？不。哪一个——你知道必须应用一些东西
to apply, otherwise it wouldn't be up here as an example. So what of the heuristic transformation
，否则它不会在这里作为例子。 那么启发式转换
supply? Elliott.
供应呢？ 艾略特。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, B bravo. Military background or something like that. Maybe
发言者 1：是的，B bravo。 军事背景之类的。 也许
he flies airplanes. OK so B says, it is in fact a function of the tangent. And when we
他会开飞机。 好的，B 说，它实际上是切线的函数。 当我们
do that, we've got to make a substitution, that y is equal to the tangent. So that means
这样做时，我们必须进行替换，即 y 等于正切。 所以这
that this becomes the integral of y to the fourth over 1 plus y squared. And that's by
意味着这成为 y对 1 加上 y 平方的四次积分。 那是通过
transformation B, and the transformation is y equals tangent of x. The tangent-- I guess
变换B，变换是y等于x的正切。 切线——我想
I've lost track of the fact that I've already transformed a y, but relabeling doesn't matter.
我已经忘记了我已经转换了 y 的事实，但是重新标记并不重要。
All right so that's progress, maybe. But don't see this in any of the heuristic transformations,
好吧，也许这就是进步。 但是在任何启发式转换中都看不到这一点，
what do I do now? I didn't have to look in the heuristic transformations, because one
我现在该怎么办？ 我不必查看启发式转换，因为其中
of the safe transformations applies. Because this thing is a rational function and the
一种安全转换适用。 因为这个东西是有理函数，
degree of the numerator is greater that the degree of the denominator, so I have to divide.
分子的次数大于分母的次数，所以我要除法。
And when I divide, and that by the way is number four, I get what? Is anybody good high
当我分裂时，顺便说一句，这是第四个，我得到什么？ 有没有好的
school algebra that can help me out with that?
高中代数可以帮助我解决这个问题？
AUDIENCE: Y squared minus 2 plus negative 2 over 1 plus y squared
听众：Y 的平方负 2 加上负2 加 1 的平方加上 y 的平方
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, y squared minus 1 plus 1 over 1 plus y squared, I think. Now what?
发言者 1：我认为，确切地说，y 的平方负1 加上 1 的平方加上 y 的平方。 怎么办？
Now we're really getting close to getting through this, because that is a sum. And by
现在我们真的快要解决这个问题了，因为这是一个总和。 并且
virtue of the fact that it's a sum, that divides into three pieces, and the top piece is the
由于它是一个和，分为三部分，顶部
integral of y squared, the middle piece is the integral of minus 1, and the bottom piece
是y平方的积分，中间是负1的积分，底部
is the integral of 1 over 1 plus y squared dy in all cases.
是1加1的积分 y在所有情况下都是 dy 的平方。
Gosh, if I look this up, I've found it. That's up there, that's letter B. So I'm done with
天哪，如果我查一下，我已经找到了。 那在上面，那是字母B。所以我已经完成
that. This one I can transform again, by virtue of 1, and now I get the integral dy. That's
了。 这个我可以再次转换，凭借 1，现在我得到积分 dy。
in there, that's B as well. As this one, I don't know. But I'd better keep track of what
在那里，那也是B。 作为这个，我不知道。 但我最好跟踪
I'm doing here. This is in the and node, so I've got to do all of those. I can't give
我在这里所做的事情。 这是在 and 节点中，所以我必须做所有这些。 我不能
up on that last thing. And that and transformation is transformation number 3. So this is in
放弃最后一件事。 那和转换是转换编号 3。所以这是
the table, this is in the table, we still have this to do, but that's C, heuristic transformation
在表中，这是在表中，我们仍然需要这样做，但那是 C，启发式转换
C. We have 1, plus y squared, then with the transformation C, with y-- this is y squared--
C。我们有 1，加上 y 的平方，然后是转换 C  , y-- 这是 y 的平方
y equals tangent of z And then we get to the integral of dz and that's in the table and,
-- y 等于 z 的正切 然后我们得到dz 的积分，这在表格中，
we're done.
我们就完成了。
So now we've solved the problem. It's the hardest problem that appeared in that half
所以现在我们已经解决了这个问题。 这是
decade on MIT 18 01 finals. This is exactly the problem that was given, except that it
MIT 18 01总决赛这五年出现的最难的问题。这正是给出的问题，只是它
started here. I put the other two pieces on just to illustrate a couple of the transformations.
从这里开始。 我把另外两件放在上面只是为了说明一些转换。
But that's a problem that it solved.
但这是它解决的问题。
And now that we've seen an example, we can finish up what we talked about a little bit
现在我们已经看到了一个例子，我们可以完成我们之前谈到的与这个东西
ago, having to do with the architecture of this thing. So far, all we've done is talk
的架构有关的内容。 到目前为止，我们所做的只是
about the safe transformations, but now we know that if we're not done, we need to find
谈论安全转换，但现在我们知道，如果我们还没有完成，我们需要找到
a problem to work on
一个问题来
using that depth of functional composition business. And then after that we apply heuristic
使用函数组合业务的深度。 然后我们应用启发式
transformation.
变换。
And the way Slagle designed his program is,
Slagle设计他的程序的方式是，
he found just one problem to work on, did one transformation,
他只发现一个问题需要解决，进行一次转换，
then went back around the loop. Because these heuristic transformations are a little harder
然后返回循环。 因为这些启发式变换
to apply than the safe ones. So I'll given you an accurate portrayal of what this program
比安全变换更难应用。 所以我会给你一个准确的描述这个程序做了什么
did, except for one thing. Which I would like, now, to go back and patch up. And that thing
，除了一件事。 我现在想回去修补。 那东西
is over here. What to do with something like this. Well we got to that in a board that's
就在这里。 像这样的事情该怎么办。 好吧，我们在一个消失的板上
disappeared, but when we tried to deal with this, we had to find a heuristic transformation.
解决了这个问题，但是当我们试图处理这个问题时，我们必须找到一个启发式转换。
And when we decided to work on this, it must have been the case that this was the simplest
当我们决定着手解决这个问题时，一定是因为这
problem at a leaf node that has not yet been solved.
是叶节点上尚未解决的最简单问题。
So what's the functional composition depth of this? It's 3. Back over here, we have something
那么这个的功能组合深度是多少呢？ 是 3。回到这里，
that has a depth of functional composition of 2. So when the program actually ran on
我们有一个功能组合深度为 2 的东西。所以当程序实际运行
this particular problem, it stopped a few inches short of the finish line, And went
这个特定问题时，它在距离终点线几英寸的地方停了下来，然后
back and screwed around with that other problem for a little bit, before it gave up and came
回去搞砸了 其他问题有点，在它放弃并
back here.
回到这里之前。
So it's always looking across the whole tree, the leaves of the tree. Whenever it has to
所以它总是看着整棵树，树的叶子。 每当它必须
find a place to work on with the heuristic transformation, it happened to look at all
找到一个地方进行启发式转换时，它碰巧会查看所有
the leaves of the tree that had not yet been dealt with, tried to find the easiest one,
尚未处理的树的叶子，试图找到最简单的叶子
and that could involve a lot of backing up and starting over on a branch of the tree
，这可能涉及大量备份并从
that it had previously ignored. A small detail, not a particularly important one.
它之前忽略的树枝上重新开始。 一个小细节，不是特别重要的。
Now where are we. We've got that guy there. We've got our complete architecture. We've
现在我们在哪里。 我们有那个人在那里。我们已经有了完整的架构。 我们已经
got our solved problem. And now we can start reflecting on what we've done. We can say,
解决了问题。 现在我们可以开始反思我们做了什么。 例如，我们可以说，这是
for example, how good an integration program is this? And the answer is, it was pretty
一个多好的集成程序？ 答案是，它非常
good. This machine that Slagle was using was a machine that was over in building 26. And
好。  Slagle 使用的这台机器是 26 号楼的一台机器。
we were so proud of it, that it was behind glass, and you could go there and watch the
我们为它感到非常自豪，它在玻璃后面，你可以去那里观看
tape spin, it was really a delight. 32k of memory, that's 32k of memory. It's amazing
磁带旋转，这真的是一种乐趣。  32k内存，也就是 32k 内存。 令人惊讶的
that he was able to do anything with a machine of that size.
是，他能够用这么大的机器做任何事情。
Let's see, let's get us a clean one. Can't do board geometry and talk at the same
让我们看看，让我们给我们一个干净的。不能同时做板几何和说话
time. We can now ask some questions about how well the program performed. It was given
。 我们现在可以问一些关于程序执行情况的问题。 它给出了
56 of the hardest problems, and it got 54 right. What happened when it didn't get the
56 个最难的问题，它得到了 54 个正确的问题。 当它没有得到其他两个时发生了什么
other two? Well, you might be right if you said, oh it probably ran out of memory, since
？ 好吧，如果你说，哦，它可能内存不足，你可能是对的，因为
it had 32k. But in fact, it just was lacking 2 transformations that were needed, in order
它有 32k。 但实际上，它只是缺少2 次转换，
to solve the whole entire set of final quiz problems. So when a program fails, that's
以解决整套最终测验问题。 因此，当程序失败时，这
often the most interesting question you can ask. This is an exception. This failed for
通常是您可以提出的最有趣的问题。 这是一个例外。
uninteresting reasons on 2 of the 56 problems that it was given to.
在给出的 56 个问题中，有 2 个因无趣的原因而失败。
And now the next question you can say is, what is the depth of the tree in the maximal
现在你可以说的下一个问题是，在最大情况下，树的深度是
case? And the answer is, it's that case we just worked out. And since I've once again
多少？ 答案是，我们刚刚解决的就是这种情况。 既然我又一次
lost the whole tree, I'll tell you that it's depth was 7 when you take off that minus 5.
失去了整棵树，我会告诉你，当你去掉负5时，它的深度是7。
So in the worst case, this thing had to get down seven levels.
所以在最坏的情况下，这东西必须下降七层。
That's the worst case, a more interesting question is what was the average depth? And
这是最坏的情况，一个更有趣的问题是平均深度是多少？
that was approximately 3. And now we're beginning to say something, not only about Slagle's
那大约是 3。现在我们开始谈论一些事情，不仅是关于 Slagle
model of how a freshman works, but we're beginning to say something about the nature of the domain.
的新生如何工作的模型，而且我们开始谈论领域的性质。
In the domain of calculus problems, integrals expressions that are given to freshman, in
在微积分问题领域，给新生的积分表达式，在
that domain, the average depth of problem reduction needed to solve the problem was
那个领域，解决问题所需的问题减少的平均深度是
3. So that's not very complicated. If it were 10, you would say, wow, how can anybody ever
3。所以这不是很复杂。 如果是10，你会说，哇，怎么会有人
do those problems? If it were 5, you'd say, well only people destined to be math professors
做这些问题？ 如果是 5，你会说，只有注定要成为数学教授的人才
are going to get anything right. If it's 3, us ordinary mortals can do a pretty good job.
会做对。 如果是3，我们普通凡人可以做得很好。
Another question of even greater interest is, how many branches were unused? Here's
另一个更令人感兴趣的问题是，有多少分支未被使用？ 这是
a branch that turned out to be unused, it didn't pursue that. And so you might say,
一个被证明没有使用的分支，它没有追求那个。 所以你可能会说
well maybe there are a lot of unused branches. Maybe you have to be pretty smart about your
，也许有很多未使用的分支。也许您必须非常聪明
method for determining what problem to work on, because otherwise you'll go down a lot
地确定要解决的问题的方法，因为否则您将陷入
of rat holes.
很多麻烦。
And guess what, here's another statement about the domain. In the domain of problems that
猜猜看，这是关于域的另一种说法。 在新生可以解决的问题领域中
freshmen could work on a final, the number of unused branches is about 1. So that means
，未使用的分支数量约为 1。这意味着
this tree keeps itself together, and doesn't run down to a very large, bushy, useless tree.
这棵树保持在一起，不会变成一棵非常大的、浓密的、无用的树。
So this means that the depth of functional composition, which Brett suggested as a technique
所以这意味着功能组合的深度，布雷特建议作为
for recognizing the right problem work on, was a choice that didn't actually matter.
一种识别正确问题工作的技术，是一个实际上并不重要的选择。
Because the tree doesn't grow deep, it doesn't go broad. It doesn't matter what you use to
因为树长不深，所以不宽。 您使用
decide what to work on, because in the worst case, you'll just generate a couple of extra,
什么来决定要处理什么并不重要，因为在最坏的情况下，您只会生成几个额外的
useless nodes. But they very quickly run to find a dead end, so you don't have to do anything
无用节点。 但他们很快就会跑到死胡同，所以你不必对他们做
more with them.
更多的事情。
So now the next thing we need to do is back even further away from this program, and ask
所以现在我们需要做的下一件事是远离这个项目，问
ourselves some questions about the nature of what we've been doing. And that brings
自己一些关于我们一直在做的事情的性质的问题。 这让
me to the things I've got on that upper right-hand board. One of those things as a catechism
我想到了我在右上角的板上的东西。 其中之一是与知识有关的教理问答
having to do with knowledge.
。
And what we've done informally as we went through this program was, we've asked questions
在我们完成这个项目时，我们非正式地做的是，我们提出了一些问题，
such as, what kind of knowledge is involved in doing this? Well knowledge about transformation.
例如，做这件事涉及到什么样的知识？ 关于转型的好知识。
Knowledge about how goal trees work and when we're done with a problem. Knowledge about
关于目标树如何工作以及我们何时完成问题的知识。 关于
what things don't need to be transformed, because you can look them up in a table. That's
哪些东西不需要转换的知识，因为您可以在表格中查找它们。 这
the kind of knowledge that is involved in doing 18 01. And if you do 18 0 circuit theory,
就是做 18 01 所涉及的知识。如果你做 18 0 电路理论、
6 0 circuit theory or 6 0 Maxwell's equations, this is the same thing.
6 0 电路理论或 6 0 麦克斯韦方程组，这是同样的事情。
You have to ask questions of this sort,
你必须问这类问题，
about the nature of the knowledge involved, and question number one is always, what kind
关于所涉及知识的性质，第一个问题总是，涉及什么样
of knowledge is involved? Is it Kirchhoff's laws, Maxwell's equations, what is it?
的知识？ 是基尔霍夫定律，麦克斯韦方程，是什么？
The next question is, how is the knowledge represented? And our answers here are, well
下一个问题是，知识是如何表示的？ 我们在这里的答案是，
all this stuff, ultimately was represented in list best expressions. Some of the
所有这些东西，最终都以列表最佳表达式表示。 一些
knowledge was recorded in a table [? of best ?] expressions to show what transformations
知识被记录在一个表中[？ 最好的?] 表达式来显示有哪些转换
there are. There was a similar table of integrals. Knowledge about goal trees was embedded in
。 有一个类似的积分表。关于目标树的知识嵌入
the procedure, so it was procedurally represented. And so for each of the categories of knowledge,
在程序中，因此它在程序上被表示出来。因此，对于每个类别的知识，
there's a way it gets represented. How is it used? Straightforward, transformations
都有一种表示方式。它是如何使用的？ 直截了当，
are used to make the problem simpler. The table is used to trim off and to serve as
转换用于使问题更简单。桌子用于修剪并用作
the bottom of the tree. Those are the ways in which the knowledge is used.
树的底部。 这些是使用知识的方式。
And then there's the question of course of, how much knowledge is required. Something
然后当然是需要多少知识的问题。
that's useful to know if it's late at night, you have 2 finals the next day, and you're
知道是否深夜有用的东西，第二天你有2个期末，你
not sure which course you should study. So how much knowledge might you suppose was actually
不确定你应该学习哪门课程。那么你认为这个程序实际上包含了多少知识
in this program? I've shown you a glimpse of the kind of knowledge that's involved in
呢？ 我已经向您展示了该计划所涉及的知识类型
the program. I've answered a little bit of question 5, what exactly. But how much knowledge
。 我已经回答了一点问题5，究竟是什么。 但是
was involved. You might be surprised by the answer.
涉及到多少知识。 你可能会对答案感到惊讶。
First of all, the table of integrals. I've listed only 3 things there. There are lots
首先是积分表。 我在那里只列出了 3 件事。
of other things you can think of, like integral of e to the x is e to the x. But in the end,
你可以想到很多其他的事情，比如e 对 x 的积分就是 e 对 x 的积分。 但最后，
what Slagle found is, a table only 26 elements was enough to solve all of these problems.
Slagle 发现，一张只有 26 个元素的表格足以解决所有这些问题。
How about the transformations here, the safe ones, about 12. How about the heuristic ones,
这里的转换怎么样，安全的，大约 12。启发式的怎么样，
about 12. So just a few bits and pieces of knowledge, here and there, are sufficient
大约 12。所以，这里和那里的一些点点滴滴的知识，就足以
to do everything you need to do, in order to do the integration problems on a calculus
完成你需要做的一切，为了做 微积分期末的积分问题
final. That was a surprise.
。 那是一个惊喜。
Another surprise of a similar kind, also about knowledge, is that the relationship between
另一个类似的惊喜，也是关于知识的，是
the method to be used, and the characteristics of the problem, was almost a diagonal table.
要使用的方法和问题的特征之间的关系几乎是一个对角线表。
That means that you could, in this domain, make the right transformation almost all the
这意味着，在这个领域，
time if you're a little bit smart, and never back up. That was an observation made by Joel
只要你稍微聪明一点，你几乎可以一直做出正确的转变，而且从不支持。 这是乔尔摩西的观察
Moses, who became subsequently our provost here at MIT for a while. And he wrote a program
，他后来成为我们在麻省理工学院的教务长一段时间。 他编写了一个
that could solve anything. It would beat the most dedicated mathematicians at integration.
可以解决任何问题的程序。 它会在积分方面击败最敬业的数学家。
And its descendents are in MATLAB today.
它的后代今天在 MATLAB 中。
But this is how it all works. And now you can write one of these things yourself. Partly
但这就是一切。 现在你可以自己写这些东西之一。 部分
because you now have this catechism. This is the kind of stuff you should ask any time
是因为你现在有这个要理问答。 这是
you're dealing with a new domain. It will make you smarter. And this is of course, meta
您在处理新域时应该询问的问题。 它会让你更聪明。 这当然是元
knowledge, this is knowledge about knowledge. So this tired aphorism isn't quite what we
知识，这是关于知识的知识。因此，这句乏味的格言并不是
are going to complete ourselves with. We're going to say that knowledge about knowledge
我们要完成的。 我们要说，关于知识的知识
is where the real power is.
才是真正的力量所在。
Now there's one final thing that this program does for us. It tells us something about our
现在这个程序为我们做了最后一件事。 它告诉我们一些关于我们
appreciation of what it means to be intelligent. You know that in the beginning of this hour,
对聪明意味着什么的欣赏。你知道，在这一个小时的开始，
I asked you to think about whether a program that could do symbolic integration would be,
我让你想一想，一个可以进行符号积分的程序
in any way, or should be considered to any degree, intelligent. And I'm imagining that
在任何方面，或者在任何程度上都应该被认为是智能的。 而且我在想象，
even in these days of MATLAB, and whatnot, many of you said well, yes, I learned how
即使在 MATLAB 的这些日子里，你们中的许多人都说好，是的，我
to do that at MIT, or late in high school, so it must be smart.
在 MIT 或高中后期学会了如何做到这一点，所以它一定很聪明。
But now that we've completed this discussion, I also expect that your feeling of intelligence
但是既然我们已经完成了这个讨论，我也希望你
in this program is somewhat diminished. Because what happens is that, when we understand how
对这个程序的智能感觉有所减弱。 因为发生的事情是，当我们了解
something works, it's intelligence seems to vanish. You've seen this in your friends,
某事物的运作方式时，它的智能似乎就消失了。 你在你的朋友那里看到过，
right? They solve some problem, they seem super smart. Then they tell you how they did
对吧？ 他们解决了一些问题，他们看起来超级聪明。 然后他们告诉你他们是怎么做到的
it, and they don't seem so smart anymore.
，他们似乎不再那么聪明了。
So let's conclude our discussion today was a little story. A long time ago I was talking
所以让我们结束我们今天的讨论是一个小故事。 很久以前，我
with a student who said, computers cannot be intelligent. And I said, OK, maybe you're
和一个学生交谈，他说，计算机不可能是智能的。 我说，好吧，也许你是
right, but let me show you this program. So I showed him the integration program, working
对的，但让我给你看这个程序。 所以我向他展示了集成程序
on problems like this. And after I showed him a couple of those examples, he says, well,
，解决了这样的问题。 在我给他看了几个这样的例子之后，他说，
all right, I guess maybe they can be intelligent. I'm learning how to do that, and it's not
好吧，我想他们可能很聪明。我正在学习如何做到这一点，这并不
always easy. Then I made a fatal mistake. I said let me show you how it works, and we
总是那么容易。 然后我犯了一个致命的错误。我说让我告诉你它是如何工作的，我们
spent an hour going through it like this. And at the end of that time, he turned to
花了一个小时来研究它。到最后，他转身对
me and said, I take it back, it's not intelligent after all. It does integration the same way
我说，我收回来，毕竟不聪明。 它以与我相同的方式进行集成
I do.
。